Guide to the Stanford University Print Collection SC1039
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Prints
  - American Field Service in France. Donation of ambulance No.478 to the U.S. Army Ambulance Service with the French Army by students and friends of Leland Stanford Jr. University and friends of the American Field Service., 1914-1918; P212; ink and colored pen on paper; 15 1/4 x 9 3/4 (Box B4)
    Army Ambulance Service
  - Southern Pacific Company, Office of the President. Letter to Henry Vrooman from Leland Stanford concerning the foundation of Leland Stanford Junior University. (San Francisco, CA) Vrooman was a lawyer retained with the railroad company. On Nov. 14, 1885, Mr. and Mrs. Stanford met with the Board of Trustees to receive the grant of land for the university and accept the trust. Vrooman was a member of the original Board., Nov. 23, 1885; P213; 10 7/8 x 13 7/8 (Box B4)
    Vrooman, Henry - Senator from Alameda County
  - A pictoral map of Palo Alto and the San Francisco Peninsula with a brief history of the area. Prepared for the city of Palo Alto by the Palo Alto Chamber of Commerce. Designed by Arthur Lites of Palo Alto., P214; 22 x 17 (Box C5)
    Lites, Arthur; Palo Alto (Calif.); Lites, Arthur
  - The original Memorial Church. Drawing by Charles Dalton Austin with watercolor. Approx. 1901., P215; watercolor; 16 7/8 x 9 1/4 (Box C5)
    Memorial Church; Austin, Charles Dalton; Shepley Rutan and Coolidge; Austin, Charles Dalton
  - David Starr Jordan. Honorary diploma - Doctor of law from Indiana University. Only segment of the original remains preserved in mylar., P216; diploma; 12 1/4 x 13 3/4 (Box B4)
  - Louis Christen Mullgardt. Design for the president's house, Stanford University, Louis Christen Mullgardt, architect., 1916 May 29; P217; 22 x 34 1/2 (Box MC)
    Mullgardt, Louis Christen; President's House; Mullgardt, Louis Christian
  - Poster: "Doctor Jordan will wear bloomers in the quad tomorrow." Published in San Francisco by Stanley Taylor., P218; 11 x 17 (Box B4)
  - Stanford, Jane Lathrop. Watercolor over photograph copy of portrait of Mrs.Stanford by Bonnat, 1881, P219; 11 x 16 (Box B4)
    Bonnat
  - "Coming: Stanford Glee and mandolin clubs; annual holiday tour.", c.1900; P220; 27 x 20 (Box D2)
    Gift of Frank Riley
    glee club; mandolin club; students
  - Time Capsule. Contents of time capsule, placed under class plate in 1917., P221 (Box B4)
    Time capsule, class of 1917
  - Hammer and Cofin Society, charter., P223 (Box MC)
    Hanner and Coffin society; students
  - Palo Alto Stock Farm, racing colors., P224; watercolor illustration (Box A4)
    Palo Alto Stock Farm
  - "Palo Alto California Tomatoes." Palo Alto brand, packed by Tillman Canning Co. at Oakland, Alameda Co. California. Canning label., P225; color print; 4 1/2 x 12 3/4 (Box A4)
    Donated by William Rambo.
  - Stanford Indian. Black and white line drawing., P226 (Box A4)
    Donated by News and Publications: 88-075.
    Stanford Indian
  - California horses in the Eastern market. The recent sale of Senator Stanford's thoroughbreds at the American Institute, New York City. From Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, April 12, 1890, p.213., P227; colored lithograph; 15 5/8 x 10 1/2 (Box B4)
  - Stanford, Leland. Obituary and portrait. From Pacific Rural Press, June 24, 1893, p.1., P228; 15 1/4 x 11 (Box B4)
  - The football team of the Leland Stanford Jr. University. From supplement to "The Wasp," December 1, 1894., Dec. 1, 1894; P229; 14 x 10 1/4 (Box B4)
    Football.
  - Hoss, Della Taylor. Woodblock prints from Mary Curry Tressider's "Trees of Yosemite," 1932. 8 prints: red fir, Ponderosa pine, incense cedar, California black oak, sugar pines, giant sequoia, & Sierra juniper., P230; 6 x 9 1/2 (Box A4)
    Yosemite; trees; Hoss, Della Taylor; Hoss, Della Taylor
  - Stanford University. Albertype miniatures. Published by Hyde's Book Store, Palo Alto, California. (c.1930) Subjects: quad views, arches, art gallery, library, Memorial Church, stadium, dormitories, Stanford Union, Basketball Pavilion, etc., P231; 3 1/2 x 2 3/4 inches (Box A4)
    Contents: c.2 with original box, from 92-042
  - From avocados to zelkovas: a sampler of Stanford trees. Compiled by Karen Bartholomew with assistance from Prof. Ron Bracewell and University Horticulturist Herb Fong., Jul-84; P232; printed on white paper; 23 x 17 1/2 (Box C5)
    trees; landscaping; Bartholomew, karen; Bracewell, Ron; Fong, Herb
  - Stanford University; bird's eye view map by Edward M. Farmer. Copyright 1934 by the Board of Trustees of the Leland Stanford Jr. University., P233; 14 x 11 (without frame) (Box SAL)
    same as Map 401
    Farmer, Edward M.; campus views; Farmer, Edward M.
  - Stephens, Richard. East gate of the Stanford quad, 1934. "This original drawing has been reproduced by photo-lithography at the Stanford University Press, and is presented as a keepsake. Dorothea and James Nute. December 25, 1934.", P234; 12 1/4 x 15 1/4 (with frame) (Box SAL)
    Inner Quad, east gate; Stephens, Richard; Stephens, Richard
  - Bassford, Wallace. Stanford scenes: Memorial Court, Stanford Union, Stadium, arcade, Memorial Curch. (c. 1940), P235; prints of sketches; 5 3/8 x 7 3/4 (Box A4)
    Bassford, Wallace; campus views; Bassford, Wallace
  - Lemos, Pedro J. Miscellaneous prints from Stanford publications. Three prints: The Ship Watchman (1926), Stanford Shepherd (1926), The Cliff Dweller (1926)., P236 (Box A4)
    Lemos, Pedro J.; Lemos, Pedro J. (Pedro Joseph), 1882-1954
  - Stanford University scenes: miscellaneous prints from publications., 1922 - 1929; P237; printed; varied (Box A4)
    Contents: 237.1 Engineering corner of the Quad (1927),; 237.2 Union Court (2 copies, 1927),; 237.3 Toyon Tower (1927),; 237.4 Union Fountain by Byron de Bolt (1927),; 237.5 Library by Leo Shapovalov (1929),; 237.6 A Stanford Autumn (1922); 237.7 Quad portal by Morgan Stedman (1928)
  - "This train STOPS 20 minutes for supper at the Golden Hotel Promontory, Utah." Mentions Golden Spike ceremony., P238; 6 x 9 (Box A4)
  - Lecture by Prof. David Starr Jordan on the New Charter. (Saturday, April 11, at Golden Gate Hall in San Francisco), P239; 9 x 12 (Box A4)
  - Stanford Days, printed photographs c. 1935. 10 images: Inner Quad, Women's Gym, Law Steps (Quad), Toyon Hall lounge, Library, front view of Quad, Memorial Church, Stadium (aerial), and montage of athletes., P240; 7 1/2 x 10 3/4 (Box A4)
    Contents: copy with portfolio from 2002-332
  - deLaunay, J. Charcoal sketch of Paul Harmon Kirkpatrick., P241; 16 1/2 x 12 (Box B4)
    Faculty; deLaunay, J.; Kirkpatrick, Paul H.; deLaunay, J.
  - Inner Quad: Arcades. Two views of Arcades: Memorial Church doors, corner looking out on an oak tree., P242; sepia toned lithograph; 12 x 9 3/8 (Box A4)
    Inner Quad
  - item transferred to AM 1994-15, P243
  - Our quadrangle. 4 art originals with a cover drawing. Unmounted, bound with ribbon within cover., P244; black ink on paper (Box A4)
  - Center for Research and Development in Teaching. "Great ideas in inner space: Westinghouse ASD Group enriches new R&D environment at Stanford.", P245; 29 cm x 43 cm (Box B4)
    Center for Research and Development in Teaching
  - "Chart of the Political Parties of the United States from the Settlement at Jamestown to the Present Day." (artist unknown) Reverse: ad for Humphrey's Homeopathic Specifics., 1889; P246; colored pencil drawing; 38 x 12 1/2 (Box MC)
    politics; medicine
  - Lathrop Family Tree; collected and arranged by John Lathrop, Buffalo, NY., circa 1870; P247; in mylar; 66 x 46 cm. (Box D2)
    Originally in wooden frame and classed as AM00-86. August 1995, removed and encapsulated; reprocessed as a print.
    genealogy; Lathrop family
  - Jewel Fund Bookplate: Clio offering gifts to Athene, circa 1914; P248.1; Pencil on paper, mounted; 20 x 28.75 inches (Box D2)
    library; bookplates; Blashfield, Edwin Howland
  - Unidentified man; possibly David Hewes or W. F. Herrick, undated; P249; pencil on paper (Box D2)
    possible id's done by visual checking in Canfield collection and BP collection
    Hewes, David; Herrick, W. F.; Canfield, Helen or Margaret
  - Boris Pasternak Centennial Conference - Program of Events; (signed by participants), Oct-90; P250; printed; 17 x 11 inches (Box B4)
    Slavic studies
  - Stanford scenes by Jim M'Guinness, P251; watercolor on prints; various (Box A4)
    Contents: 251.1 Old post office; 251.2 University Avenue, P.A., 1931; 251.3 Memorial Church facade
  - David Starr Jordan [sketch by F.S. Campbell, signed by David S. Jordan], 1910; P252; ? [not original drawing]; 4.75 x 7.75 inches (Box A4)
    Jordan, David Starr; Campbell, F. S.
  - Clio offering gifts to Athene, circa 1914; P248.2; Pencil on paper, framed; 20 x 25 in. (approx) (Box DSS office)
    Clio is standing in this version; not used as the bookplate
  - Pure Grape Brandy Senator Leland Stanford's Vina Distillery, circa 1890; P253; lithograph, colored; 15 x 12.5 inches (Box B4)
    Includes photo of vineyard, each different; Advertising placard; 2002-294 (framed) is on loan to Gordon Earle - ret. 5/08
    Contents: 253.1 [center photo is B & W] + one mounted facsimile; 253.2 [center photo is cyanotype]; 253.3 [center photo is cyanotype] 2002-294
    Vina Ranch
  - Stanford Scenes. Stanford University Press pub. Color photographs of 4 campus views: Hoover Tower, Memorial Church interior, Memorial Church exterior, University Library., circa 1950; P020.2; 10 x 13.5 inches (Box A1)
    Includes original envelope and brochure
  - Award of Achievement [to] Stanford University in furthering the objectives of the Civil War Centennial, Sept. 9, 1965; P254; mounted certificate; 8.25 x 11 inches (Box A4)
    Civil War Centennial
  - Print of painting of David Starr Jordan by Spencer Machy (1922), unknown; P255; print; 6 3/8 x 7 3/8 inches (Box A4)
    Had been framed and cataloged as AM 00-208
    Jordan, David Starr; Machy, Spencer
  - David Starr Jordan - sketch of, with Latin inscription "indagator scientiae dvx praestans rervm maxime propvgnator pacis", unknown; P256; lithograph (?); 10.5 x 10.5 on 13 x 16 mat (in) (Box B4)
    Mat is signed by Jordan; latin = investigator of science, excellent leader of affairs, and most of all great defender of peace
    Jordan, David Starr; Richard, Winifred
  - Cecil H. Green sheet - text of placard for 1980 dedication, P257; printed; 26 x 41 inches
    Libraries; Green, Cecil H.
  - Stern, Alec. Stanford Chapel., P258; etching; 22.5 x 17.5 inches (Box D2)
    same view as P028 but with differences in technique; top edge glue to cardboard backing
  - Memorial Church facade and arcades, 1987; P259; ink on paper; 17 x 7 3/4 inches (Box B4)
    has plastic overlay for printing purposes; prepared for Cornerstone Weekend
    Memorial Church; Inner Quad; McClean, Joanna
  - Stanford scenes by Ken Gaylord, 1984; P260; Print; 14 x 11 inches (Box A4)
    4 items, 2 signed in pencil
    Contents: 260.1 History corner; signed #4/50; 260.2 Memorial Church facade; signed #2/50; 260.3 Quad gate and portal; 260.4 The Claw and facade of Stanford Union
    quad; white plaza;; Gaylord, Ken
  - Student scenes (imaginative) by Sara Boore, 1982; P261; photostat copies; 3.5 x 3.5 inches (Box A4)
    used for illustrative purposes
    Contents: 261.1 Two students fooling with hula hoops; 261.2 Students in a huddle with sweaters that say "humanities", "engineering", "social sciences"; 261.3 Student hiding under bed with textbooks on bed
    Students; Boore, Sara
  - Stanford Images: Hoover Tower; Terman Engr. Bldg., undated; P262; multi format (Box A4)
    262.1 glued to larger paper
    Contents: 262.1 Hoover Tower [photostat]; 262.2 Terman Engr. Bldg.? [ink on paper]
    Hoover Tower; Angelesco, F.
  - Trustees' resolution on Menlo Park's 100th anniversary, calligraphied by Hans Wehrli, 1974; P263; photostat copy; 11 x 14 inches (Box A4)
    Menlo Park (Calif.); Wehrli, Hans
  - Resolution of gratitude to George E. Osborne by Stanford Law School, calligraphied by Hans Wehrli, 1972; P264; ink on paper,; 15 x 20 inches (Box C5)
    unsigned; right edge torn
    Law School; Osborne, George E.; Wehrli, Hans
  - Resolution in honor of Walter C. Peterson [probably by News & Pubs], calligraphied by Hans Wehrli, 1973; P265; pencil on vellum; 15.5 x 20.5 inches (Box C5)
    Peterson, Walter; staff; Wehrli, Hans
  - M'Guinness, Jim. Stanford illustrations. 4 boxes, P266; various; many (Box SAL)
    originals and copies of his illustrations for various Stanford pubs
    Contents: see other listing
    M'Guinness
  - Mendelsohn, Barbara. Illustrations for Stanford publications, P267; many (Box SAL)
    Mendelsohn, Barbara
  - Resolution of indebtedness to Lloyd William Dinkelspiel by the Board of Trustees, June 19, 1958; signed by Ira Lillick and David Packard, P268; copy of original??? (Box D2)
    Board of Trustees; Dinkelspiel, L.W.; Ferris, Warren W.
  - "At the Play" respectfully inscribed to the Wealth, Enterprise and Beauty of California by their faithful friend, Frederick Marriott. Supplement to the July 19, 1879 San Francisco Newsletter, reissued, August, 1883. Lithograph by Britton and Rey. Also, an article from the San Francisco Sunday Chronicle, April 9, 1961, describing the print, a black-and-white print of the lithograph, and a key to the lithograph., July, 1879; P050 (Box B2)
  - "At the Play" respectfully inscribed to the Wealth, Enterprise and Beauty of California by their faithful friend, Frederick Marriott. Supplement to the July 19, 1879 San Francisco Newsletter, reissued, August, 1883. Lithograph by Britton and Rey. Also, an article from the San Francisco Sunday Chronicle, April 9, 1961, describing the print, a black-and-white print of the lithograph, and a key to the lithograph., July, 1879; P050 (Box C2)
  - A. Errmelao Paoletti and Salviati and Company. Drawings for mosaics of Memorial Church. Includes Aurora de Guido Reni., P042.54 (Box D1)
  - [USGA Resolution of gratitude to Stanford University Golf Course for entertaining the 12th Junior Amateur Championship], Aug. 8, 1959; P269; calligraphy; 11 x 15.5 inches (Box B4)
    embossed and illuminated
    Golf
  - Reading room, Green Library West, circa 1970; P270; ink and watercolor; 18.25 x 13.74 inches (Box B4)
    ink drawing on illustration board with watercolor; some damage to surface
    Green Library; Students; M'Guinness, Jim
  - [Stanford University Law School]. Print with watercolor, no. 4/100, circa 1976; P271; framed; 18 x 10.5 in. [frame] (Box GW 403)
    Law School; M'Guinness, Jim
  - Stanford University Bookstore check for $3,100,000 to Stanford University Libraries, Juyly 20, 2000 [oversize facsimile mounted on foamcore, used in presenation ceremony], P272; 35.25 x 16.25 inches (Box map case)
  - Posters and illustrations, P273; printed
    Kataoka, Drue.
    - Golf images
      - Notah Begay III, 273.1 (Box 1)
      - 8th Annual Big Game Cup, 1999 Nov; 273.2 (Box 1)
      - California – Stanford Golf Invitational, 1999 Apr; 273.3 (Box 1)
      - California – Stanford Golf Invitational, 2000 Apr; 273.4 (Box 1)
    - Men's Basketball images
      - Stanford basketball – "Mad Dog Madsen", 273.5 (Box 1)
      - Stanford basketball – "The Art of the Steal", 273.6 (Box 1)
    - Guarding the Tradition: 25 Years of Stanford Women's Basketball 1999-2000
      - Kate Starbird, 273.7 (Box 1)
      - Jamila Wideman, 273.8 (Box 1)
      - Molly Goodenbour, 273.9 (Box 1)
      - Kate Paye, 273.1 (Box 1)
      - Sonja Henning, 273.11 (Box 1)
      - Jennifer Azzi, 273.12 (Box 1)
    - Football images
      - Hundredth Big Game, 1997; 273.13 (Box 1)
      - Stanford Legends – John Elway and Jim Plunkett, 273.14 (Box 1)
    - Stanford Events/Lectures
      - Stanford Asian American Awards 2000, 273.15 (Box 1)
      - Stanford Asian American Awards 2000, 273.16 (Box 1)
      - Stanford Asian American Awards 2000, 273.17 (Box 1)
      - 32nd Annual Carlos McClatchy Memorial Lecture 1998 – James Fallows, 273.18 (Box 1)
      - 33rd Annual Carlos McClatchy Memorial Lecture 1999 – Howard Kurtz, 273.19 (Box 1)
      - 34th Annual Carlos McClatchy Memorial Lecture 2000 – Gwen Ifill, 273.2 (Box 1)
      - Martin Luther King Jr. Millennium Celebration 2000, 273.21 (Box 1)
    - Non-Stanford images
      - Boys and Girls Club Jump Rope Junction 2001, 273.22 (Box 1)
      - Rotary International Highway Hopscotch 2002, 273.23 (Box 1)
      - Pacific Riminiscences 3.10.05; Commissioned by Pacific Art League, 273.25 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous
      - The Sally Ride Science Club presents reach for the stars science festival for girls. San Diego [2001]. Poster signed by Kataoka and Ride, 273.24 (Box 1)
      - Holiday cards for Hoover Institution (Box 1)
      - Booklet for S. U. Department of Electrical Engineering with cover art by Kataoka (Box 1)
      - Booklet for S. U. Department of Physics with cover art by Kataoka (Box 1)
      - Copy of Cardinal Today, Nov. 22, 1997 (on Big Game) with two illustrations by Kataoka (Box 1)
      - Two articles on Kataoka (Box 1)
  - Snoppy Quop [character from the Chaparral], circa 1912; P274; pencil on paper; 8 x 9.75 inches (Box A4)
    Chaparral; Murray, Feg
  - Stitching a Century: The Stanford Centennial Quilt March 9, 1991, P275; print; 18x24 inches (Box C5)
    found in frame behind AM 2001-10
  - The California wonder Occident, owned by Gov. Leland Stanford. -- New York: Currier & Ives, 1873. Photo historians believe this print was taken from the Edward Muybridge photo, now lost., P209c.2; 13 xc17.5 inches (Box B3)
    In this copy the colors are more intense.
  - "Illegal Spirit in Black and White", artwork done in 1994; printed as serigraph edition in 2001 in conjunction with Galarza Memorial lecture. Print numbered 2 of 35., P276; serigraph print (Box MC)
    Chagoya, Enrique; Chagoya, Enrique
  - Ernesto Galarza Memorial Lecture, Jose R. Padilla, May 11, 2001. Features "Illegal Spirit in Black and White" by Enrique Chagoya. signed by Chagoya., P277; Serigraph print (Box MC)
  - Hoover Tower as seen from Meyer Library, includes Green East and proposed (?) west wing., circa 1970; P278; B/W film over colored pencil; 21.5 x 40.5 in. (mat) (Box MC)
    Back of matting bears Planning Office stamp with the year 1970
    Hoover Tower; Barkley
  - Hommage a Leibniz. Text concerns Leibniz's invention of a binary system of notation. English version is dedicated to Donald E. Knuth. Each item signed by Hermann Zapf., circa 2000; P279; printed; 12.5 x 19 inches (Box B4)
    Contents: 279.1 German version; 279.2 English version
    Zapf, Hermann
  - Stanford football program images ca. 1930s (these are not actual program covers), circa 1930; P280; printed; 11 x 15 inches (Box B4)
    Contents: 280.1 Stanford - SCSC; 280.2 Stanford - Washington; 280.3 Southern California - Stanford; 280.4 Stanford - Dartmouth
  - Caricatures of Stanford rugby team and Coach Maloney, ca. 1924, circa 1924; P281; printed; 10 x 9.5 inches (Box A4)
    Rugby football.; LeMessurier
  - Stanford football players relaxing; printed version of original pencil drawing, 1953; P282; printed; 13.5 x 11.5 inches (Box B4)
    includes xerox of newspaper clipping with drawings of basketball players by Brodie, ca. 1962
    Football.; Brodie, Howard
  - Resolution of Thanks to Dan Fiduccia by Stanford Daily for work on Zurcher v. Stanford Daily legal case; callilgraphy by Vitero, 1979; P283; hand caligraphy; 10.75 x 17 inches (Box B4)
    Removed from frame 12/18/01
    Vitero
  - Dust jacket for 1940 Stanford Quad, P284; printed (Box C5)
    transferred from 4digit collection
  - David Starr Jordan, portrait with signature (not manuscript), circa 1920; P285; printed; 9.5 x 12.5 inches (Box A4)
    Removed from GP as it is not a true photograph [was GP 12698]
  - Where the Rolling Foothills Rise: framed color prints from the publication, 1919; P286; print, framed; 18.25 x 11.5 inches (Box Own box)
    Box 1 = 286.1 - 286.6; Box 2 = 286.7 - 286.12
    Contents: 286.1 Explanatory text; 286.2 Elms on Salvatierra Street; 286.3 Burning eucalyptus bark in the Arboretum; 286.4 Behind the quadrangle; 286.5 Portal of the LSJU Museum; 286.6 In the Quadrangle; 286.7 Stanford Mausoleum; 286.8 Monterey Pines; 286.9 Giant Redwoods in the Portola Valley; 286.10 Encina, the Live Oak; Roble, the White Oak; 286.11 Memorial Church and NW Arch; 286.12 Along the curving road the the Quadrangle
  - Memorial Church through the arches - tinted photo (or possibly a print), framed, post 1906; P287; framed print; 13.75 x 11.75 (frame) (Box B4)
    Possibly from view book published by Hyde; xerox of text pasted on back.
    Memorial Church
  - Layout of one floor of the Stanford's San Francisco residence, P288; hand made; 12.5 x 12.5 in (Box B4)
    Seems to be part of a display, possibly of photos of the house interior. Removed from GP oversize; gift of Stanford Museum in 1968,
    Stanford residences; unknown
  - Caricature sketches of members of Beta Theta Pi. Includes Winstead "Doodles" Weaver., circa 1936; P289; printed; 18 x 24.5 in (Box C5)
    Removed from GP oversize. Identification based on correspondence with membership of Beta Theta Pi in Quads.
    Robert Etienne, James Forestal Kurtz, Carlton Hugh Beal, Winstead "Doodles" Weaver, Robert M. Bacon, Eliot M. Blanchard
    Rudolph Gonzalez, Robert Hall, Charles Henry Holt, Fredrick Harper, Jack Dunbar Middleton, William Orr Boswell
    Clement Eyer Smoot, Philip Brown, Peter Atkinson Luppen (or Luppe H. Luppen??), Michael Gonzalez, Roger Allen Pearson, Robert Fullerton,
    ? Torrence, ? Ingersoll, Richard Bernard Daugherty, William Ray Kantzer, Richard James Forhan, Najeeb Elias Halaby
    Names compiled from class lists in 1955 Alumni Directory and from Quad pages on the Beta Theta Pi fraternity.
    Fraternities; Students; Weaver, Doodles; Ward
  - Military appointment for John Hewston Jr. signed by Governor Leland Stanford, April 3, 1863, P172.2; Printed with seal and signatures; 16.5 x 21.25 inches (Box C4)
    Hewston, John
  - Military appointment for John Hewston Jr. signed by Governor Leland Stanford, May 12, 1862, P172.1; Printed with seal and signatures; 16.5 x 21.25 inches (Box C4)
  - Sunlit Arches. signed in pencil: Pedro J. Lemos. Embossed "Stanford Library", P290; print, sepia tones; 11 x 15.5 in (Box B5)
    found in "in process" drawer in SAL map case
    Lemos, Pedro J. (Pedro Joseph), 1882-1954
  - Across the Quad - Stanford. signed in pencil: Pedro J. Lemos. Embossed "Stanford Library", P291; print, sepia tones; 11 x 15.5 in (Box B5)
  - Robinson, Edgar E. - pencil sketch by Peter Van Valkenburgh, 1932; P293; pencil on paper; 12.5 x 19 in (Box B5)
    in acid free portfolio; found in "in process" drawer in SAL map case
    Robinson, Edgar E.; Van Valkenburgh, Peter
  - Adams, E. D. - pencil sketch by Peter Van Valkenburgh, 1928; P294; pencil on paper; 12.5 x 19 in (Box B5)
    Adams, E. D.; Van Valkenburgh, Peter
  - Jenkins, Oliver P. - pencil sketch by Peter Van Valkenburgh, 1928; P295; pencil on paper; 12.5 x 19 in (Box B5)
    glued to board; found in "in process" drawer in SAL map case
    Jenkins, Oliver P.; Van Valkenburgh, Peter
  - Original sketch of James Joyce, 1976; P296; ink & wash on paper; 14 x 22 inches (Box C5)
    Joyce, James; Momaday, N. Scott
  - Dormitory notices found in Encina east wing 1960s, P297; printed (Box A4)
    Contents: 297.1 Encina and Toyon information and regulations (ca. 1947?); 297.2 Telephone instructions; 297.3 "The Iniated [sic] Tramp" - comic interview
    Student life.
  - The Leland Stanford Junior University, Palo Alto, issued with Christmas Number S. F. News Letter, 1889, P298; lithograph; 24 x 17 inches (Box D2)
    Another copy (encapsulated) found in unprocessed prints 6/2006.
    Stanford University -- History.; Britton & Rey, Lithographers